瓦雷利亚末日
伊耿一世（AC1-37 在位）
“征服者”
坦格利安家族征服维斯特洛
雷妮丝
伊耿一世的妹妹和妻子
伊尼斯一世（AC37-42 在位）
杰赫里斯一世（AC48-103 在位）
“和解者”“人瑞王”
亚莉珊（AC36-100）
“善良王后”
杰赫里斯一世的妹妹和妻子
贝尔隆（AC57-101）
“勇敢的”“春晓王子”
杰赫里斯一世的儿子和国王之手
阿莱莎（AC60-84）
贝尔隆的妹妹和妻子
戴蒙
“浪荡王子”
贝尔隆的儿子 韦赛里斯一世的弟弟
科利斯·瓦列利安
“海蛇”“潮汛之主”
雷妮丝
“无冕女王”
韦赛里斯一世的堂姐
韦赛里斯一世
“安宁王”
奥托·海塔尔
韦赛里斯一世的国王之手
阿莉森·海塔尔
奥托的女儿 韦赛里斯一世的第二任妻子
伊耿·坦格利安
“大伊耿”
韦赛里斯一世和阿莉森的长子
海伦娜·坦格利安
韦赛里斯一世和阿莉森的女儿
大伊耿的妻子
伊蒙德·坦格利安
韦赛里斯一世和阿莉森的次子
戴伦·坦格利安
韦赛里斯一世和阿莉森的三子
阿莉森·海塔尔
奥托的女儿 韦赛里斯一世的第二任妻子
伊耿·坦格利安
“大伊耿”
韦赛里斯一世和阿莉森的长子
伊蒙德·坦格利安
韦赛里斯一世和阿莉森的次子
海伦娜·坦格利安
韦赛里斯一世和阿莉森的长女
大伊耿的妻子
伊耿·坦格利安
“小伊耿”
戴蒙和雷妮拉的长子
韦赛里斯·坦格利安
戴蒙和雷妮拉的次子
改编自 《血与火：坦格利安王朝史》
[美] 乔治·马丁 著
龙 王 家 族
第一季 第九集
绿党会议 The Green Council
塔雅
王后的侍女
你确定？
You're sure?
阿莉森·海塔尔
摄政王后 奥托之女
他亲眼所见 陛下
With his own eyes, Your Grace.
呆在这里 不要告诉任何人
Stay here. Tell no one.
帮我更衣
Help me dress.
奥托·海塔尔
王后的父亲 国王之手
都谁知道了？
Who knows?
我的侍女 塔雅
My handmaiden, Talya.
一些仆人
Some of the servants.
当我昨晚见到他……
I saw him last night...
在他还没——
before he--
他告诉我他想立伊耿为王
He told me he wished for Aegon to be king.
千真万确
It is the truth.
他亲口所说
Uttered with his own lips.
他对我说了遗言 我是唯一听到的
His last words to me and I was the only one to hear it.
现在他死了
And now he's dead.
泰兰·兰尼斯特
凯岩城公爵杰森的双胞胎弟弟 海政大臣
什么事急成这样？
What is it that could not have waited an hour?
多恩打起来了？
Was Dorne invaded?
贾斯皮·威尔德
法务大臣
克里斯顿·科尔
御林铁卫
国王死了
The King is dead.
欧维尔
大学士
林曼·毕斯柏里
财政大臣
我们哀悼“安宁王”韦赛里斯……
We grieve for Viserys the Peaceful...
哀悼我们的国王……
our sovereign...
哀悼我们的朋友
our friend.
哈罗德·维斯特林
御林铁卫队长
但他给我们留了一个礼物
But he has left us a gift.
他用最后一口气 向王后诉出了遗愿：
With his last breath, he impressed upon the Queen his final wish:
他的儿子 伊耿……
that his son, Aegon...
应当继位为七国之主
should succeed him as Lord of the Seven Kingdoms.
既然他有此遗愿 我们也可以安心
Then we may proceed now with the full assurance
继续长久以来的计划
of his blessing on our long-laid plans.
是的 有很多事情要做
Yes. There is much to be done,
如我们之前所讨论的
as we've previously discussed.
都城守备队队长中有两位
Now, there are two among the captains
依旧忠诚于戴蒙
of the City Watch that remain loyal to Daemon.
把他们换掉
Let us replace them.
兰尼斯特大人？
Lord Lannister.
国库在掌控之中
The Treasury is well in hand.
出于安全考虑 金子将会分开保存
The gold will be divided for safekeeping.
向我们的盟友 奔流城和高庭 送去渡鸦
Let ravens be sent to our allies, Riverrun and Highgarden.
如我理解无误 御前会议的成员
Am I to understand that members of the small council
一直都瞒着我 密谋把我儿子推上王座？
have been planning secretly to install my son without me?
没必要让你沾染阴谋 王后陛下
My Queen, there was no need to sully you with darkling schemes.
我不同意
I will not have this.
亲耳听到你们竟然在密谋
To hear that you are plotting
要顶替掉国王选定的继承人！
to replace the King's chosen heir with an imposter!
国王的长子不能算是顶替者
His firstborn son is hardly an imposter.
有数百名领主大人和有产骑士向对公主宣誓效忠
Hundreds of lords and landed knights swore fealty to the Princess.
那是差不多20年前的事 大多数人如今都死了
That was some 20 years ago. Most of them now dead.
你听到国王之手大人的话了
You heard the Lord Hand.
无论密谋与否 国王改变他的主意了
Plot or no, the King changed his mind.
我如今七十有六
I am six-and-seventy years old.
我认识韦赛里斯的时间比在座的各位都要长
I have known Viserys longer than any who sit at this table.
我绝不会相信他在病榻上独身一人的时候 说出了这种话
And I will not believe that he said this on his deathbed, alone,
只有那孩子的母亲作证
with only the boy's mother as a witness.
这是强夺！
This is seizure!
这是偷窃！这是叛国！
It is theft! It is treason!
这起码是——
At the least, it is--
注意你说的话 林曼
Mind your tongue, Lyman.
国王昨晚还好好的……
The King was well last night...
大家都见到了
by all accounts.
在座的哪位敢发誓 他是自然死亡的？
Which of you here can swear that he died of his own accord?
毕斯柏里伯爵 你在指控在座的哪位弑君？
Which of us are you accusing of regicide, Lord Beesbury?
我不关心是你们哪一位 还是集体谋划的
Whether it was one of you, or all of you, I care not.
我绝不会参与——
I will have no part--
坐下！
Sit down!
克里斯顿爵士
Ser Criston.
扔掉剑 脱下你的白袍 克里斯顿爵士
Throw down your sword and remove your cloak, Ser Criston.
我是你的队长 克里斯顿爵士
I am your Lord Commander, Ser Criston.
把剑扔了
Cast down your sword.
我无法忍受王后陛下遭受冒犯
I will not suffer insults to Her Grace the Queen.
我没被冒犯 克里斯顿爵士 你—— 把剑放下
There was no insult to me, Ser Criston. Y-- Put aside your blade.
有必要这样么？
Has it come to this?
队长 够了
Lord Commander, enough.
把毕斯柏里伯爵搬走吧
Let us have Lord Beesbury removed.
不
No.
在我们完事之前 大门必须紧闭
The door remains shut until we finish our business.
风息堡是个问题
Storm's End is of concern.
我们不知道博洛斯公爵是否忠于我们
We may not assume the loyalty of Lord Borros.
但是他有四个女儿 全部未婚
But he has four daughters, all of them unmarried.
合适的婚配——
The right proposal--
雷妮拉怎么办？
What of Rhaenyra?
当然不能放前任继承人自由
The former heir cannot, of course, be allowed to remain free
为她的主张去拉拢支持
and draw support to her claim.
你的意思是要囚禁她
You mean to imprison her.
她和她的家人将有机会
She and her family will be given the opportunity
向新国王公开宣誓服从
to publicly swear obeisance to the new King.
她绝不会屈膝臣服
She will never bend the knee.
戴蒙也不会 你懂他的
Nor will Daemon, which you know.
你打算杀掉他们
You plan to kill them.
而且在座的都同意
And all here accede to this.
您的父亲是正确的 陛下
Your father is correct, Your Grace.
一个活着的挑战者会带来战争与杀戮
A living challenger invites battle and bloodshed.
是 这当然不光彩
It is unsavory, yes.
但这是为了伊耿继位做出的必要牺牲
But a sacrifice we must make to secure Aegon's succession.
而且还要考虑到戴蒙
And then there is Daemon to consider.
国王当然不希望任何不光彩的——
The King wouldn't wish for any unsavory--
但国王绝不会想要……
But the King did not wish...
他女儿被谋杀！
for the murder of his daughter!
他爱她 我不允许你否认这点
He loved her. I will not have you deny this.
但——
And yet--
再多说一个字 我就把你赶出房间
One more word and I will have you removed from this chamber
发配长城！
and sent to the Wall!
您有何建议 陛下？
What do you suggest, Your Grace?
时间宝贵
Time is of the essence.
维斯特林队长……
Lord Commander Westerling...
带着你的骑士们去龙石岛
take your knights to Dragonstone.
要干净利落
Be quick and be clean.
我是御林铁卫队长
I am Lord Commander of the Kingsguard.
除了国王我谁也不认
I recognize no authority but the King's.
现在还没有国王……
And until there is one...
这里也就没有我的位置
I have no place here.
我想 我们的宿命就是渴求别人所拥有的
It is our fate, I think, to crave always what is given to another.
海伦娜·坦格利安
韦赛里斯与阿莉森的女儿
如果一个人拥有一样东西 另一个人就会将之夺去
If one possesses a thing, the other will take it away.
是的 公主
Yes, Princess.
伊耿去哪了？
Where is Aegon?
不在这啊
Not here.
他怎么没在自己房间里
He's not in his rooms.
父亲
Father.
怎么了？
What's happened?
- 你父亲他... - 木板底 凶兽倚
-Your father-- -There is a beast beneath the boards.
哦 我亲爱的
Oh, my dearest love.
伊蒙德·坦格利安
韦赛里斯与阿莉森的次子
伊利克·卡盖尔
亚历克的孪生兄弟 御林铁卫
伊利克爵士
Ser Erryk.
王子去哪了？
Where's the Prince?
首相大人恕罪 我不知道
Forgive me, Lord Hand. I do not know.
但你发誓保护他
But you're sworn to protect him.
他下了命令 让我必须离开
He exploits his authority to order me away,
又躲着不让我找到 大人
and then he evades me, my Lord.
他大概已经偷偷离开红堡
I believe he may have left the Keep secretly,
混进了城里
gone into the city.
去找他
Find him.
只带上你哥哥
Take no one else but your brother.
把白袍脱了
And remove your white cloaks.
别让人知道你们是谁 在找什么……
None can know who you are or what you seek...
王后也不行
including the Queen.
遵命 大人
My Lord.
直接带他来单独见我 伊利克爵士
Bring him to me, and me alone, Ser Erryk.
雷妮丝·坦格利安
“无冕女王” 韦赛里斯一世的堂姐 科利斯的妻子
这是干什么？
What is the meaning of this?
卫兵 卫兵！
Guard. Guard!
拉里斯·斯壮
“弯足” 赫伦堡伯爵
红堡里没有伊耿王子的踪迹 陛下
Prince Aegon's not to be found within the castle walls, Your Grace.
您父亲已经派伊利克爵士去城里找他了
Your father has sent Ser Erryk into the city to find him.
伊利克爵士了解伊耿 他有优势
Ser Erryk knows Aegon. He has the advantage.
我会再次相信你和你的忠诚 克里斯顿爵士
I trust again to you, Ser Criston, and to your loyalty.
必须找到伊耿 带他来见我
Aegon must be found, and he must be brought to me.
事关七国的命运
The very fate of the Seven Kingdoms depends on it.
看在你对我 对你的王后的情分上
Everything you feel for me as your Queen.
我不会让您失望
I will not fail you.
我和你一起去
I'll come with you.
你不能去 伊蒙德
That would not be my desire, Aemond.
万一出了什么事——
If anything has happened--
科尔需要我 母亲
Cole needs me, Mother.
了解伊耿习性的 不只伊利克爵士一个人
Ser Erryk isn't the only one who knows Aegon's doings.
在我第十三个命名日那天 伊耿带我来了丝绸街
Aegon brought me to the Street of Silk on my thirteenth name day.
他说这是作哥哥的职责
It was his duty as my brother, he said,
确保我像他一样受过教导
to ensure I was as educated as he was.
至少我是这么理解的
At least that's what I understood him to mean.
我没明白
I don't follow.
他说“是时候滋润一下那话儿了”
He said, “Time to get it wet.”
每个女人都是圣母的化身 不能说这种亵渎的话
Every woman is an image of the Mother, to be spoken of with reverence.
昨晚 我们有位酒友不知去向
Sometime last night, we...misplaced our drinking companion.
我们知道他过去经常来照顾你们的生意
Knowing that he has been, in the past, a patron of your fine establishment,
就想着来打听他的下落
we thought to inquire here as to his whereabouts.
他长什么样
And describe him.
这件事很敏感
That is a delicate matter.
跟你直说吧 我们在找年轻的伊耿王子
You see, the man we seek is the young Prince Aegon.
希望你们干这一行的口风不会让我失望
I may trust, I hope, in the discretion of your trade.
王子不在这
The Prince is not here.
那他来过吗？或许早些时候？
Has he been here? Earlier, perhaps?
那可太早了 上次来是几年前了
Quite a bit earlier. Years ago, in fact.
最近呢？
But more recently?
他不常来丝绸街
He does not frequent the Street of Silk.
众所周知 他的品味.……
His tastes are known to be...
没那么讲究
less discriminating.
什么意思？
Meaning what?
祝你好运 好爵士 祝你朋友更加好运
I wish you luck, good Ser. And my best to your friend.
你都长这么大了
How you've grown.
韦赛里斯修改了遗愿
Viserys amended his wishes.
就这么简单
It's as simple as that.
你们曾宣誓效忠雷妮拉
You once swore your banners to Rhaenyra.
现在 你们必须宣誓效忠未来的国王
You must now pledge them to the future king.
事关重大 我得先和我的族人商议
I must confer first with my house on this matter.
不明表立场 你就不能走出这个房间
You'll not leave this room without declaring your intention.
阿伦·卡斯威
我不做背誓者
I am no oath breaker.
我不会屈膝
I will not bend the knee.
还有谁？
Anyone else?
费尔家族将继续效忠公主
House Fell keeps its sworn oath to the Princess.
很好
Very well.
国王万岁
Long live the King.
看来你也不怎么了解伊耿的喜好啊
It seems you were mistaken as to Aegon's habits.
他可能已经被雇佣兵抓走
He could be in the hands of mercenaries,
跟着船去夷地了
on a ship to Yi Ti.
也可能已经死了
He could be dead.
看在你母亲份上 但愿不会那样
Let us hope, for your mother's sake, that is not the case.
咱来看看
Let's have a look.
- 去吧 - 过来 过来！
-Go on. -Come here. Come here!
给我上去 你个小——
Get in there, you little--
耶！
Yeah!
上啊！
Come on!
他们多大？
How old are they?
十岁左右吧
About 10 years, I should say.
这些人让孩子们蓄指甲 磨尖牙
They have them grow their nails and file the teeth.
好让他们更难对付
Makes them more formidable.
上啊！
Come on!
伊耿王子在这度过了许多个夜晚
Prince Aegon spends many a night in this place.
现在你知道他是什么德行了？
Do you see now what he is?
你还没看到他的全部呢
You've not seen everything.
伊耿的种?
Aegon's?
我打赌 只是其中之一
One of many, I'd wager.
我这么一个训练有素的战士 在城里四处搜寻
Here I am, trawling the city, ever the good soldier
那个对自己与生俱来的权利毫不关心的废物
in search of a wastrel who's never taken half an interest in his birthright.
认真学历史 学哲学的人是身为次子的我
'Tis I the younger brother who studies history and philosophy,
努力练剑的人是我
it is I who trains with the sword,
骑乘世界上最大的龙 那也是我
who rides the largest dragon in the world.
我才是那个应该——
It is I who should be--
别人轻松得到 我们却得努力去争取 我知道那种滋味
I know what it is to toil for what others are freely given.
我们是找不到他的 科尔
And we can't find him, Cole.
你是个不愿堕落的体面人
You are a decent man with no taste for depravity.
他有自己的秘密……
His secrets are his own...
就让他留着秘密吧
and he's welcome to them.
我是铁王座的下一顺位继承人
I'm next in line to the throne.
如果他们来找我
Should they come looking for me,
我不会躲起来
I intend to be found.
必须做点什么 伊耿不适合做统治者
Something must be done. Aegon is unfit to rule.
你都已经容忍王子的癖好这么多年了
You tolerated the Prince's proclivities for years.
只因这是我的誓言职责 亚历克
Because it was my sworn duty, Arryk.
把动脑子的事留给首相吧
It's for the Hand to find wisdom.
我们只要至死服从发过的誓言就好
We swore an oath of service until death.
打扰一下 佬爷
A moment of your time, m'lords.
我们可不是你的顾客
You'll find no buyers for your wares here.
我可以带你们去见伊耿王子
I can take you to Prince Aegon.
或者说 有个知道王子在哪里的人派我过来
Rather, I am sent by one who knows where he is.
那人会告诉你们 但要收钱
Who'll tell you, for a price.
带他过来 我们再聊聊价钱
Deliver him, and we'll consider your price.
我们夫人可不跟红堡里的仆从打交道……
My mistress will not treat with the servants of the Keep...
虽然你们也很高贵
exalted though they may be.
但她只信任国王之手
She'll trust this to the Hand of the King only.
不可能
Impossible.
我相信他会想听听白蛆要告诉他什么
I think he will wish to hear what the White Worm can tell him.
停！别开门！
Halt! Hold the gate!
放开我！
Let go of me!
他准备从大门出逃
He was fleeing from the gate.
你们知道我是谁吗?
Do you know who I am?
我打赌是要给公主送信
A warning for the Princess, I'd wager.
你怎么说?
What say you?
御前审问长想多了
The Lord Confessor presumes.
我对公主没有偏爱
I have no love for the Princess.
那你急急忙忙要去哪里?
And where were you going then with such urgency?
让御前执法官带下去吧
Let the King's Justice take him.
放开我！
Let go of me!
不！这是不对的！
No! This is not right!
你做得很好 拉里斯大人
You did well, Lord Larys.
我一定会——
I will--
尽我的职责罢了 首相大人
Only my duty, my Lord Hand.
你以为你是谁？
Who do you think you are?
你最近和王后待在一起的时间很长
You've spent many hours with the Queen of late.
这些时间或许终究会让您受益
There's no reason those hours could not, in the end, benefit you.
韦赛里斯·坦格利安一世
国王
出于礼貌 我愿意假定
I will do you the considerable courtesy of assuming
我今早在这里受到的冒犯有个合理的原因
there is a good reason for the outrage of my treatment here this morning.
我为失礼表示诚挚的歉意
My sincerest regrets for the lack of ceremony.
国王……
The King.
而你在谋划篡夺王位
And you are usurping the throne.
是我夫君临终的遗愿
It was my husband's dying wish.
不管你信不信都无关紧要
Believe it or no, it is of no consequence.
伊耿将会成为国王
Aegon will be king.
我来这里是想让你支持我
I came here to ask your support.
我得赞赏你的胆量
Well, I must credit you for your boldness.
瓦列利安家族早就跟雷妮拉公主结盟了
House Velaryon has long allied itself with the Princess Rhaenyra
但你得到了什么?
and what has it gained you?
你女儿孤零零地……死在潘托斯
Your daughter dead... alone in Pentos.
你儿子被戴绿帽
Your son cuckolded.
雷妮拉的继承人都不是你们家族的后代
Rhaenyra's heirs are none of yours.
是你丈夫如此轻率地想要攫取王座
It is your husband who grasps so heedlessly for the throne.
他甚至也抛弃了你
And even he has abandoned you:
孤注一掷地打了六年仗
gone these six long years to fight a desperate battle,
回来时身受重伤 或许是致命伤
returning grievously, if not mortally, wounded,
留下潮头岛夫人独自规划航线
leaving the Lady of Driftmark to chart her course alone.
我们家的族语可不是反复无常
The word of my house is not fickle.
我知道不会 但是 亲爱的堂姐……
No. But, dear cousin...
你比当今世上任何人都更明白我现在说的话
you more than any soul alive understand what I say now.
雷妮丝公主 我很爱我的夫君 但我必须说出我们都知道的事实
Princess Rhaenys, I loved my husband, but I will speak the truth we both know.
你本该是女王
You should've been queen.
我可没想过能听到你这么说
I little thought to hear those words from you.
无论血脉还是气质 铁王座都应该是你的
The Iron Throne was yours by blood and by temperament.
韦赛里斯本可以做个乡下领主
Viserys would've lived his days a country lord,
狩猎 研究他那些历史 满足地过完一生
content to hunt and study his histories,
但是……事已至此
but... here we are.
我们不能统治 但我们可以指导男人统治
We do not rule but we may guide the men that do.
柔和地……
Gently...
远离暴力和毁灭 让国家走向和平
away from violence and sure destruction and instead toward peace.
你把我关在这里是为了和平吗?
Is it in the name of peace that you've imprisoned me?
我的龙怎么办?
And what of my dragon?
如果我们处于劣势
If we are overmatched,
雷妮拉一定会袭击我们 随后就是战争
Rhaenyra will be tempted to strike us, and war will ensue.
如果没有你的龙 我们或许可以说服她谈判
Without your dragon, she may be persuaded to negotiate.
如果你想要潮头岛 它就是你的
If it's Driftmark you want, you shall have it
给你和你的外孙女 或传给你中意的人选
for you and your granddaughters to pass on as you see fit.
你比我想象中聪明
You are wiser than I believed you to be...
阿莉森·海塔尔
Alicent Hightower.
真正的王后会为子民权衡得失
A true queen counts the cost to her people.
可你还在为男人劳碌
And yet you toil still in service to men.
你父亲 你丈夫 你儿子
Your father, your husband, your son.
你渴望的不是自由
You desire not to be free,
而是在你监牢的墙上开一扇窗
but to make a window in the wall of your prison.
你从来都没想过自己……
Have you never imagined yourself...
坐上铁王座吗?
on the Iron Throne?
你在这好好想想吧
I'll leave you with your thoughts.
想好了就摇铃
Ring the bell when you have an answer.
殿下你瞧
My Prince.
梅莎丽亚
“白蛆” “小梅夫人”
我想你就是神秘的白蛆吧
You yourself are the mysterious White Worm, I take it.
或者你也只不过是这颗臭洋葱上剥下的又一层皮？
Or are you simply a further peel in this stinking onion?
我为国王的驾崩致哀
My condolences on the passing of your king.
伊耿王子在哪儿？
Where is Prince Aegon?
我想 王子正在跳蚤窝呢 那儿的人可没法信任
I thought, the Prince is in Flea Bottom where no one is to be trusted.
我最好把他偷偷藏在一个安全的地方……免得有人来找他
I'd best secrete him somewhere safe... in case they come looking for him.
王子在哪儿？
Where's the Prince?
他已经被安全地藏起来了
He is safely tucked away.
我希望停止对跳蚤窝孩子们的野蛮奴役
I want an end to the savage use of children in Flea Bottom.
他们被迫相互厮杀 甚至更糟……
They are forced to fight, and worse...
你那些金袍子收了贿赂 对此视而不见
your gold cloaks take the bribes given them to look away.
而朝廷对这种无耻之行不是纵容就是无视
An obscenity either tolerated or ignored by the crown.
我会关注此事
I'll look into it.
我向你保证
You have my word.
等你的计谋得逞
When your plots ripen
外孙登上王位之时
and you install your grandson on the throne,
记住 那都是源于我的扶持
remember it was me who put him there.
我要是想杀他 容易得就像拍死水果上的黄蜂
I could have killed him as easily as a wasp on fruit.
没有民众的支持 你们哪来的权力
There is no power but what the people allow you to take.
我会记住的
I will remember.
听着
Listen.
不……不！
No... No!
不！
No!
白蛆在哪儿？
Where is the White Worm?
她把你卖了个好价钱
She sold you for a price.
你们凭啥给她钱？
And why have you paid it?
伊耿·坦格利安
“大伊耿” 韦赛里斯与阿莉森的长子
我要见我妈
I want my mother.
你的外公 国王之手 在城外等你
Your grandfather, the Hand, will meet you outside the city walls.
他人拼死而不得的东西你却不想要 伊耿
You flee what other men die seeking, Aegon.
真是遗憾 朋友
I do regret this, friend.
不要！住手！不要
No! Stop! No.
我巴不得你消失呢
I was hoping you disappeared.
咱爸真死了？
Is our father truly dead?
对……而且他们打算让你当国王
Yes... and they're going to make you king.
- 不要！- 你到底帮不帮忙？！
-No! -Are you going to help me?!
不要！放开我！
No! Let me go!
你兄弟呢？
Where's your brother, huh?
放开我！
Let me go!
弟弟！
Brother!
放开我！
Let me go!
我不想统治！
I have no wish to rule!
也没责任感！我根本不合适
No taste for duty! I'm not suited.
这点我倒是不反对
You'll get no argument from me.
放我走吧 我会找艘船 远走高飞
You let me go, I will find a ship and sail away,
永远消失
never to be found.
王后正等着呢
The Queen awaits.
这步棋走得好
Well played.
这可不是游戏
None of this is a game.
但你依然把它当成游戏
And yet you treat it as one.
一场激动人心的竞赛
A charming contest,
奖品是一袋银币
the prize, a pouch of silver.
我们相互倚仗这么多年
We have relied on one another these many years.
现在正是争取家族利益的时机 这是我们共同的期望
And now it is the good of the family that we both desire.
无论有何分歧 我们总是一条心
Whatever our differences, our hearts remain as one.
我们从来不是一条心
Our hearts were never one.
我现在明白了
I see that now.
我不过是你的一枚棋子罢了
Rather, I have been a piece that you moved about the board.
若真如此 我还让你成为了七大王国的王后
If that is true, then I made you Queen of the Seven Kingdoms.
你不也想要吗？
Would you have desired it otherwise?
我怎么知道？
How could I know?
我的想法都是你灌输的
I wanted whatever you impressed upon me to want.
现在要还债了
And now the debt comes due.
你过去很乐于还的债
A debt you were happy enough to pay.
是牺牲
A sacrifice.
为了王国稳定而做出的牺牲
A sacrifice made for the stability of the realm.
还没有哪个国王不会为了保护多数人
No king has ever lived that hasn't had to forfeit
而牺牲少数人
the lives of a few to protect the many.
不过我理解你的道德洁癖
Though I understand your squeamishness.
不愿杀人不是弱点！
Reluctance to murder is not a weakness!
伊耿在我手上
I have Aegon.
之后怎么办 由我决定
We'll proceed now as I see fit.
我们给龙石岛的雷妮拉开出条件
We will send terms to Rhaenyra on Dragonstone.
真诚的条件 这样她才能体面地接受
True terms, such that she may accept without shame.
如果她活着 她的盟友都会打着她的旗号
If she lives, her allies will mass behind her banners,
期盼她回来
looking for her return.
那她就不能回来
Then she must not return.
我的丈夫也会希望自己女儿得到宽待
My husband would have desired this mercy be shown to his daughter.
你丈夫？
Your husband?
还是你 他女儿的儿时闺蜜？
Or you, his daughter's childhood companion?
克里斯顿·科尔会被任命为御林铁卫队长
Criston Cole will be named Lord Commander of the Kingsguard.
我儿子明日黎明接受涂油礼
My son will be anointed tomorrow at dawn.
他必须在全君临的见证下登基
The whole of King's Landing must witness his ascent.
他要确立权威 事不宜迟
He will assume authority. There will be no more dithering.
我的儿子与征服者伊耿同名 也将继承他的王冠
My son will take the crown of his namesake, the Conqueror,
和他的宝剑黑火
and carry Blackfyre, his sword.
人们将记起坦格利安家族的古老力量
Let the people remember the ancient strength of House Targaryen.
在某些方面 你真像你母亲
You look so much like your mother in certain lights.
如你所愿
As you wish.
陛下
Your Grace.
现在已经很晚了 拉里斯大人
The hour is late, Lord Larys.
我发现了一件应当告知您的事
I've found out something that you should know.
不知道你是否疑心过……
Have you asked yourself, I wonder...
你父亲……国王之手…
how it is...that your father, the Hand...
是怎么先找到伊耿的？
found Aegon first?
这红堡中的眼线织就了一张蛛网
There is a web of spies at work in the Red Keep.
丝线传递着我们的一举一动
Along its threads travels news of all our doings.
你父亲明知如此 却不予理会
Your father knows this, but has left it in place.
事实一次次证明 只要你愿意供养织网人
More than once, it has proved advantageous to those willing to...
便可得利
feed the weaver.
而这个织网人在监视我？
And this weaver watches me?
有只小蜘蛛就是你的侍女
One of the little spiders is your lady-in-waiting.
塔雅？
Talya?
像她这样的还有更多
There are more like her.
尽管我不知道人数
Even I do not know their number.
有个法子可以摧毁他的优势
There is one way to destroy his advantage.
擒贼擒王
It must be taken out at the head.
没了蜂后 蜂群就是一盘散沙
When the Queen dies, the bees fly without purpose.
陛下 请原谅我作此比喻
Begging your pardon for the turn of phrase, Your Grace.
看来这件事正好是你的专长
I assume this task falls within your expertise.
只要您有意……
If you wish it...
事会办妥的
it will be done.
让开
Out of my way!
伊利克·卡盖尔
亚历克的孪生兄弟 御林铁卫
跟我来 公主
With me, Princess.
我不会纵容如此背信弃义
I cannot let this treachery stand.
我们在哪？
Where are we?
国王路南边一点
Just south of King's Way.
去黑水河走这边
The Blackwater's this way.
我不能抛下梅丽亚斯
I won't leave Meleys.
如果我能去龙穴的话——
If I could get to the Dragonpit, then--
不行 他们料定你会出现在那 公主
No. They'll expect you there, Princess.
你进不了大门的
You won't get past the gates.
来吧
Now come.
你得到河边找艘船
You must make for the riverfront and find a ship.
趁他们还没发觉你走了
Before they know you've gone.
赶紧 快走
Move it! Go! Go!
这边
This way!
就这样 动起来
Keep moving! That's right.
就这样
That's right!
继续向前
Onward!
这边
This way.
停！停！
Halt! Halt!
动起来
Keep moving!
所有人 往前走！
All of you, move forward!
动起来
Keep moving!
别挡路
Out of the way!
七神在上 今日吾王 伊耿二世……
……力寻正义 智辨是非 祈求圣母……
祈求战士 升平之际 赐武于锋 赐勇于……
……王国富庶 祈求少女 看护王后……
……暗中之路 祈求陌客 敬勿登门 直至终……
七神在上 我们感谢诸神之慈悲与荣光 赞美诸神之智慧……
遥想征服者 伊耿一世……
土浸鲜血 剑铸王座
七神在上 我们臣服于诸神之裁决 国王屈膝于……
王亦如是 我们铭记 灾祸降临圣堂……
老妪高举明灯 叛贼无处遁形 我们赞美……
此地龙穴 今日盛典……
七神在上 赐福祝圣 我们祈求 您之忠仆……
……先民 七国之王 全境守护者……
愿天父救他于危难 愿老妪举她之……
慈悲七神 涤尽吾等之罪 回报吾等之忠……
抵御吾等之敌
此为“征服者”伊耿一世的瓦雷利亚钢王冠，有别于韦赛里斯一世的黄金王冠。
起码做做样子 感激感激吧
Have the decency to look grateful.
你能有今天 知道我做了些什么吗
Do you know what has been done to give you this day?
一小时后 你就是国王
In an hour, you will be king.
父亲从来不是这样想的
And my father never wanted this.
并不是
That's not true.
20年来他随时可以指定我作继承人 却从来没有
He had 20 years to name me heir and never did.
他坚定地为雷妮拉的权利撑腰
Steadfastly, he upheld Rhaenyra's claim.
他改了主意
He changed his mind.
哇 呵呵 哪有……
Oh...No...
他可以 但从来没有
He could have, but he never did
因为他不喜欢我
because he didn't like me.
然而在他临终时
And yet, with his final breath,
还是轻声跟我说 该由你来接替他继承王位
he whispered to me that you should take his place on the throne.
别戏弄我了 老妈
Do not toy with me, Mother.
这是真话
I speak the truth.
听着 伊耿
Listen to me, Aegon.
你外公 国王之手 会给你灌输观念
Your grandfather, the Hand, will try to impress on you
说雷妮拉应该被处死
that Rhaenyra should be put to the sword.
你必须拒绝这一建议
You must reject this counsel.
我们绝不能靠残暴和冷漠统治
We must not rule with cruelty and callousness.
不管她有什么错 她都是你姐姐 你父亲的女儿——
For all her faults, she is your sister, your father's daughter--
你爱我吗？
Do you love me?
你个笨蛋
You imbecile.
为王家车驾让道
Make way for the royal wheelhouse!
嘿 嘿 前进啊
Hey, hey, forward then.
继续 动起来 快点
Go on, move yourself! Come on!
龙穴正门上方的高等瓦雷利亚文字 Tego ēlior vēttir dāro lyks kessa 意为
“全境的第一律法就是以国王之名维护和平”，是伊耿一世征服维斯特洛后颁布的法令。
君临人民
People of King's Landing...
今天是最悲伤的一天
today is the saddest of days.
我们敬爱的国王
Our beloved king...
“安宁王”韦赛里斯
Viserys the Peaceful...
驾崩了
is dead.
但今天也是最喜悦的一天
But it is also the most joyous of days...
因为在他的英灵离开之际
for as his spirit left us...
他喃喃道出了遗愿：
he whispered his final wish:
要由他的长子伊耿……
that his firstborn son, Aegon...
继任王位
should succeed him.
卫兵
Guards!
让路 闪开
Out of the way! Move!
立正！
Halt!
转身！
Turn!
举剑……
Present...
行礼！
arms!
得以见证此刻
It is your great good fortune
实乃尔等万幸与荣光
and privilege... to be here to witness this:
这是城市的新纪元
a new day for our city...
亦是王国的新纪元
a new day for our realm.
引领我们的新国王
A new king... to lead us.
愿战士赐勇气于其身
May the Warrior give him courage.
愿铁匠注力量于其剑盾
May the Smith lend strength to his sword and shield.
愿天父助其于患难
May the Father defend him in his need.
愿老妪以明灯引其于路途
May the Crone lift her shining lamp and light his way to wisdom.
征服者之冠代代相传
The crown of the Conqueror, passed down through generations.
恭请七神见证
Let the Seven bear witness:
伊耿·坦格利安即铁王座的真正继承人
Aegon Targaryen is the true heir to the Iron Throne.
伊耿二世
All hail His Grace, Aegon,
安达尔人 洛伊拿人
Second of his Name,
和先民的国王
King of the Andals and the Rhoynar and the First Men,
七国统治者
Lord of the Seven Kingdoms
暨全境守护者万岁
and Protector of the Realm.
伊耿国王！
Aegon the King!
此为坦格利安家族的瓦雷利亚钢剑“黑火”，曾为“征服者”伊耿一世所使用。
伊耿国王 伊耿国王万岁！
Aegon the King! Long live Aegon!
梅丽亚斯
雷妮丝的龙
开门！
Open the doors!
保护海伦娜
Get Helaena.